

export const riddles = [
    {
        id: '101',
        question: `I have no finger but i point, no arm but i
        strike, no feet i run what am i?`,
        answer: "clock"
    },
    {
        id: '201',
        question: `"I never was, am always to be,
        no one ever saw me, no ever will, but yet I'm 
        the confidence of all who live and breath.
        "`,
        answer: "tomorrow"
    },
    {
        id: '301',
        question: `What must be broken before yeast?"`,
        answer: "egg"
    },
    {
        id: '401',
        question: `Am hopeless to one, but priceless
        to two. what am i?`,
        answer: "love"
    },
    {
        id: '501',
        question: `You regine me when am lost, you retain me when am found, what am i?`,
        answer: "trust"
    },
    {
        id: "601",
        question: "I am a daily sickness in man, what am i ?",
        answer: "hunger"
    },
    {
        id: "701",
        question:` You buy me to eat, but never eat me , what am i?  `,
        answer: ` Silverwere `
    },
    {
        id: "801",
        question: "What cost nothing but is very hard to find and can easily be lost? ",
        answer: "true friendship"
    },
    {
        id: "901",
        question: "What ends everything always ?",
        answer: "g"
    },
    {
        id: "201",
        question: "I fly without wings and cry without eyes, what am i ? ",
        answer: "cloud"
    },
    {
        id: "202",
        question: "I can bring tears to your eyes, resurrect the  dead, make you smile, and reverse time. I form in an instant but i last a life time. What am i?",
        answer: "love"
    },
    {
        id: "203",
        question: "What three words are said too much, yet not enough ?",
        answer: "i love you"
    },
    {
        id: "204",
        question: "Take off my skin and i won't cry, but you will, what am i ?",
        answer: "onions"
    },
    {
        id: "205",
        question: "What kind of ant is really good at math ?",
        answer: "accountant"
    },
    {
        id: "206",
        question: "The more you take the more your leave behind, what am i ?",
        answer: "footstep"
    }, 
    {
        id: "207",
        question: "I am tall when young and short when i am old. what am i ? ",
        answer: "candle"
    }, 
    {
        id: "208",
        question: "I get smaller everytime i take a bath, what am i ?",
        answer: "candle"
    },
    {
        id: "209",
        question: "I fly without wings, what am ?",
        answer: "cloud"
    },
    {
        id: "301",
        question: "If you loose me yu may cause people around me to loose me as well, what am i ?",
        answer: "anger"
    }, 
    {
        id: "302",
        question: "You own me but everyone used me more than you do, what am i ?",
        answer: "name"
    },
    {
        id:"303",
        question: "I can fall off a building and live, but put me in water and i will die, what am i ?",
        answer: "paper",
        explaination: "paper is so light that even if it fall from the clouds it will still remain in one piece, but if it get into water it will be destroy"
    },
    {
        id: "304",
        question: "The faster you run, the harder it is to catch up with me ",
        answer: "breath",
        explaination: "The faster you run the hard it get to catch your breath"
    },
    {
        id: "305",
        question: "I dissappear everytime you say my name, what am i ?",
        answer: "silence",
        explaination: "Everytime you speak the silence present dissappears or replace with the sound of your voice"
    },
    {
        id: "306",
        question: "You can see me, but you can't touch me, You flip a switch i'm in the house, You flip it again i'm gone, what am i ?",
        answer: "tv station",
        explaination: "Everytime you press your tv remote it bring up a station, you can only see it but can't actually touch it "
    }, 
    {
        id: "307",
        question: "I can sneak up on you, or stay in front of you,  you can't see me , but when i review mysef to you, it changes your whole life, what am i ?",
        answer: "betrayal",
        explaination: "You will never expect to be betrayed , still it is review to you"
    },
    {
        id: "308",
        question: "I am a son of water but if water touches me , i will die, what am ? ",
        answer: "salt",
        explaination: "Salt is get distroyed when it touches water, salt is also a mineral of water"
    },
    {
        id: "309",
        question: "I am the reviewr of masks, when i appear friends becomes foe, and the one that you love, becomes the one you hate, what am i ?",
        answer: "betrayer",
        explaination: "when Betrayer is reviewed , friends, family and lover becomes your foe and hate"
    },
    {
        id: "401",
        question: "I live to expand, i give all, i take nothing, i can raise you to a king or a begger, what am i ?",
        answer: "love",
        explaination: "Anyone can fall in love. kings, begger, midde class, lower class all can fall in love",
    },
    {
        id: "402",
        question: "I can lend you a hand, but you wont' find me helpful, my name may sound tasty, but the flavor is dreadful, what am i ?",
        answer: "knockle sendwitch",
        explaination: " The name may sound like a delicous food, but when you are being  giving it hurt and wish you were not given after all"
    }, 
    {
        id: "403",
        question: "I strike where you lie, death gentle coursin, what i am ?",
        answer: "sleep",
        explaination: "sleep is just 50% of death or almost like death but you are just half conscious."
    },
    {
        id:"404",
        question: "My shot are perfect, the greates artist, i am the best photographer in the world, what am i ?",
        answer: "mirrow",
        explaination: "picture perfect like no other in the world"
    },
    {
        id: "405",
        question: "Something you have , but you leave in every single thing you touch, what am i ?",
        answer: "fingerprint",
        explaination: "You always leave a finger print in everything you touch"
    },
    {
        id: "406",
        question: "You tell me all your problem, the good, the bad, the past, the future, the present and probabily the future as if you want me to advice you, but am always quite. what am i ?",
        answer: "dairy",
        explaination: "Your dairy take in everything about you and even your present"
    }, 
    {
        id: "407",
        question: "I lost a head when comes morning and gets a head at night, what am i ?",
        answer: "pilow",
        explaination: "You lie on the pilow at night and leave the pilow in the morning"
    },
    {
        id : "408",
        question: "I have a brother, but we hardly see eye to eye, what am i ?",
        answer: "sun and moon",
        explaination:"sun and moon hardly meet "
    }, 
    {
        id: "409",
        question: "What is the answer to everything, when you think you have it , you don't , what i am ?",
        answer: "knowledge",
        explaination: "knowledge is the foundation to everything  , but when you feel or thing you have it , you have it not because the more we learn the more we realized how little we know and how much more their is to discover, it a never-ending pursuit."
    },
    {
        id: "501",
        question: "I can make you laugh or make you cry, you can't run from me, when you die , you become me yourself, what am i ?",
        answer: "memories",
        explaination: "Because good memories and bad memories exist  within you and when you die , you become a memory to others."
    },
    {
        id: "502",
        question: "I have no legs none hands, i move in the same  directions but in three different pace, what am i ?",
        answer: "time",
        explaination: "Time have no physical hand nor leg, and can more in 3 different direction, Fast(when having fun), Medium(during a typical day), Slow(when you are waiting for something)"
    },
    {
        id: "503",
        question: "We were given birth on the same day, Beautiful to all, me and my brother only meet once in a hundred years, what are we?",
        answer: "sun and moon",
        explaination: "sun and moon are both created the same day, they are both celestial bodies that been present in our solar system since it's foundation. Both of them are both beautiful and captivative. they both meet once in a hundred years, as the sun and moon align in a rare ceestia event know as a'Centennia eclipe', which occurs approximately once every 100 years."
    },
    {
        id: "504",
        question: "I am the youngest of all things created, I inherited all, but also the distruction and solution to them all, what am i ?",
        answer: "human",
        explaination: "Human are indeed the youngest if you good through Biblical history or grand scheme of evolution. Human have inherited the earth and all it's resources from generations and from the natural world. But they are responsible for the destruction of the environment and at the same time have the capacity for creativiy,innovation and problem-solving and are working to find solution to the world's problems."
    },
    {
        id: "506",
        question: "A bitter feeling comes my heart, a painful thought that covers my soul, My happy eyes become very sad, when it sees you, what am i ?",
        answer: "death",
        explaination: "Death is powerful and poignant theme, it captures the emotional pain and sadness that comes with it."
    },
    {
        id: "507",
        question: "The sweet test of honey, that beat that make my heart dance and make me feel loved. what am i ?",
        answer: "happiness",
        explaination: "happiness captures the sweet, uplifting and loving feeling . the sweet taste of honey is a perfect metaphor for the joy and delight that comes with happiness,  the 'beat that makes my heart dance' suggest the energetic and carefree feelings that accompany happiness"
    }


]



